Advertise My Property

* **Rent a property**

* **Sell a property**

* **Other**

[Home](https://publish.daft.ie/) / information **50,418** properties online (666 in the last 24 hours)

Daft Privacy and Cookie Policies
================================

Last updated on 5th October, 2020

### Contents

Privacy Policy
--------------

Introduction
------------

Your privacy is important to us.

This privacy policy has been created to explain how and why we collect and use information about our users, and how we manage your privacy protection. We recommend that you read this statement in full, so that you understand how we will use your personal data. You can also read about specific issues by clicking on one of the topics below.

### Table of Contents

What personal data do we collect?
---------------------------------

Daft collects personal data to operate our business and to provide you with the product and services that we offer. You provide some of this data to us directly, for example when you open an account with us, contact an advertiser on the site, or send a query to our support team. Other data is collected when you interact with our products, by using cookies and other technologies.

When using our site, you have choices about what data we collect, and when you are asked to provide personal data you may decline. If you decline to provide data that is necessary to provide you with a particular product or feature, you may not be able to use this product or feature.

We collect personal data in the following ways:

1\. Through information you provide to us.
------------------------------------------

When you register with us as a user, you provide us with some personal data such as your name and email address, which we will store in order to create your account. We will also store information relating to any further use of our service, when you contact another user of the site through our platform, the contents of the emails you send to them and any other information that you may upload to the Sites. Finally, we may also collect information from any correspondence that you have with us.

2\. Through your use of our services.
-------------------------------------

When you use our services, we collect information about what types of services you use and how you use them. For example, which parts of our websites you visit, and what advertisements you view. The information that we collect while you use our services can be grouped into the following categories:

* _Information about your device and internet connection_

Using technical logs and other tools, we register information about the device you use, such as the device manufacturer, operating systems and browser version. We also collect information about the connection to our services, such as IP address, network ID, cookies and unique ID files. This information can help us to adapt the way content is displayed to you, based on your device and user profile.

* _Information about how our services are used_

We also register information about how you use our services. For example, which pages of the site you visit, the searches that you have performed, the times and dates that you visited our site, how long a page is displayed on your screen, how you navigate around the page, which websites you have visited before visiting our site, what functions you have carried out on a page, and if you have completed a transaction.

* _Cookies and other locally stored content_

When you use our services, cookies and other data are stored locally on your device. These cookies provide us with information that we can then read. You can find more information about cookies, how and why we use them, and how to manage them in our [Cookie Policy](#cookies).

* _Information about user location_

We register your geographical location based on your IP address and mobile network code.

* _Messages_

We collect information about when you send or receive messages from other users of our site.

Legal Basis for Processing
--------------------------

We process your Personal Data in order to ensure the necessary performance of your contract with us. In certain circumstances, we may also process your Personal Data for the purposes of our legitimate interests, such as to inform you of changes to our services, to provide you with information about other services we offer, or in order to comply with any legal obligations to which we are subject.

We may also rely upon your consent as a relevant legal basis for processing your Personal Data. In the event you wish to withdraw your consent to the collection and processing of your Personal Data in this manner, please follow the links below:

1. [My Daft](https://www.daft.ie/my-daft/account-settings/)

How We Use Your Personal Data
-----------------------------

We use the data that we collect to provide you with the products and services that we offer. This allows us to improve the products that we offer you and to personalise your experience on our site. We may also use the data to communicate with you, to inform you about your account and to provide you with security updates. Where you have consented for us to do so, we may also use your data to contact you in relation to updates about our own products, products provided by third parties, and to help to show you more relevant adverts on the site.

Your data will be used by us to authenticate your account and to enable you to interact with other users of our site.

* _Contacting advertisers_

When you contact an advertiser through our site, we will use the personal data that you have provided as part of this contact to connect you to the advertiser and in some circumstances, any developer the advertiser represents - for example, new home developers represented by agents. The advertiser and developers will receive a copy of any data that you have entered as part of your message to them.

* _Communications_

We will contact you via email and messages posted on our website or apps. These messages will communicate about service related issues and security updates. Where you have consented for us to do you, we will also contact you with promotional marketing materials from us and from our partners. You can update your marketing preferences at any time within your account. Please note that it will not be possible to opt out of receiving service messages from us. This includes messages relating to security and legal notices. We may issue marketing materials to the properties that are listed on our platform for the purposes of advertising our services to the occupiers of such properties.

* _Advertising_

Banner advertising on our site is targeted to visitors of the site through a variety of ad networks and exchanges. We also use this data to measure the performance of these adverts. We use the data that you provide to us, through your cookie preferences, either separately or combined to achieve this.

* _Research and Developing Our Services_

We use data that we collect through your use of our site and through public feedback, to conduct research and develop our services based on our findings. This allows us to provide you with a better experience when using our site.

* _Customer Support_

We use the data that you provide to us, including your communications, to investigate and respond to service issues and complaints.

* _Insights_

We use your data to generate statistics about our site that do not identify you using third-party assets such as cookies. Please see our [Cookie Policy](#cookies) for more details. These statistics provide us information about how our site is used, the number of ad impressions served or clicked on, and the demographic distribution of visitors to our site.  
On various pages of our website, we record visitor behaviour and serve polls/surveys via [HotJar](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy). Visitor behaviour is recorded anonymously through click heat maps for each page [HotJar](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy) is implemented and also through recordings of visitors interacting with the site. For visitor recordings, all personally identifiable information is whitelisted including searches. [HotJar](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy) also enables us to serve surveys and polls. These surveys are optional and in most cases, we don't ask for or receive any personally identifiable information. Where we ask for an email address/phone number, the users needs to consent before the survey is submitted.  
We also use a third party called [Wootric](https://www.wootric.com/company/privacy/) to measure customer satisfaction for Daft. Site visitors are asked how likely they are to recommend the site to a friend and given the option to submit a comment on their experience with the site. There is no personally identifiable information stored.

* _Security Monitoring and Investigations_

We will use your data when necessary to investigate and identify possible fraudulent behaviour on the site and possible attempts to harm other members or visitors to the site. We will also use your data to investigate violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy.

How we Share Your Information
-----------------------------

We retain access to all personal information that we have collected from you. If you have consented on signup or on the appropriate email form, we may provide any of the information we collect to carefully screened third parties to contact you regarding products or services that we think may be of interest to you. If Daft enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed to our new business partners or owners.

* _Our Services_

Our service allows you to engage with other members of our site. If you send a message to another member of our site, your message will be shared with that site member.

* _Service Providers_

We engage other service providers to help us to provide our service to you. For example, to process payments, site maintenance and fraud detection. These service providers will have access to your information as much as is reasonably necessary for them to perform these tasks on our behalf. They are obligated not to disclose or use your data for any other purpose.

* _Legal Disclosures_

When required to by law, we may disclose information about you. This may be as a result of a subpoena or other legal process. Your personal information will also be shared if we believe that the disclosure is necessary to

1. Be used by government enforcement agencies investigate, prevent or take action against any suspected or actual illegal activities.
2. To enforce the agreements that we have with you.
3. To investigate and defend Daft against any allegations made by third parties.
4. To protect the integrity and security of our services.
5. To exercise the rights and safety of Daft, our employees and other users of our service.

* _Change of Ownership_

If Daft enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed to our new business partners or owners in preparation for, or as a result of, any of these events. Any other entity which buys Daft or any part of our business, will have the right to continue to use your data in the way described by this privacy policy, unless you consent otherwise.

Your Rights and Choices
-----------------------

The General Data Protection Regulations offer you a number of rights in relation to your data. This includes the right to access a copy of your data, a right to receive a copy of your data that can be transferred to another organisation, a right to data deletion, a right to withdraw your consent to data processing, a right to restrict the processing of your data, and information on any automated decision making processes.

* _Data Retention_

The amount of time that we retain data for, depends on the type of data being retained, and how that is used. In some cases, there will be a legal requirement for us to hold data for a specified amount of time. In other cases, we will not retain the data for any longer than necessary for the purpose that it was collected and processed.

When you register an account with us, we will retain the personal information that you provide to us for as long as you hold this account. Once an account has been closed, we will continue to retain this personal data for a period of seven years. This timeframe is in line with the Irish statutory limitation periods. If you don't actively close your account with us, it automatically become inactive after 3 months of you not accessing it. After this, the personal data you have provided us will be retained for seven years.

All other data provided, which is not personally identifiable, will be retained for possible future use, including details outlined in section 10 of the [Terms & Conditions](https://publish.daft.ie/legal#content). If you have provided data to us without registering an account, this data will be retained for 7 years after your last date of activity with us.

* _Right to Access Your Personal Data_

Non-registered and registered users of the Sites can request we provide them with a copy of the personally identifiable information we hold by using our data request feature.

* _Right to Control Your Personal Data_

Registered users of our site can update their information by using our data request feature or contacting our Customer Support Team directly. You can also edit and make changes to the personal information by logging into your account and editing it directly from there. You can change your marketing and contact preferences at any time in your account dashboard by opting out receiving of these communications. You may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that such information is accurate and kept up-to-date.

* _Right to Data Deletion_

Non-registered and registered users of our sites can request we delete any personally identifiable information we hold by using our data request feature. In some instances we may be unable to delete your data if we are required to retain it to comply with our legal obligations (including requests from law enforcement agencies).

* _Right to Data Portability_

Registered users of our site have the right to data portability. This means that you can request that a copy of your data is made available in a structured, commonly used and machine readable form that can be transferred to you or to another organisation. You may request a portable copy of your data by using our data request feature.

Other Important Information
---------------------------

* _Special Category Personal Data_

Daft does not collect any special categories of personal data. However, if you enter this information into any free text section of our site, such as the ad description, or on our forums, this information will be held and processed in the same manner as all other data that you have provided to us.

* _Security_

The security of your data is important to us. We perform regular monitoring of our systems to identify possible vulnerabilities and attacks. However, we cannot warrant the security of any information that you send to us. No guarantee is given that the data will not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

* _Direct marketing_

We will only send you marketing information where you have opted in to receive these communications. You can change your marketing preferences at any time, by logging into your account and changing this on your account dashboard. You can also opt out of receiving marketing at any time using the unsubscribe link that can be found at the end of each email that we send.

* _Changes to this Statement_

This statement will be updated when necessary to reflect changes that we make to our products. When this statement is updated, the "last updated" date will be revised at the top of this statement. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy regularly so that you can stay informed about our use of your data.

* _Contact information_

If you have any questions in relation to this Policy, please contact our Data Privacy Officer at [dpo@daft.ie](mailto:dpo@daft.ie). You can also contact us by writing to  
  
Data Privacy Officer  
Distilled SCH  
Latin Hall  
Golden Lane  
Dublin 8.

If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you have the right to contact your local Data Protection Commissioner. In Ireland, they can be contacted via their website [here](https://www.dataprotection.ie/).

Cookie Policy
-------------

What are cookies and how are they used?
---------------------------------------

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your device's web browser by a website and is stored on your \*device's hard drive. Cookies may allow a website to "remember" your actions or preferences over a period of time, or they may contain data related to the function or delivery of the website. Each website can send its own cookies to your web browser. Your browser will have the option to prevent websites using cookies (your browser's help screen will tell you how to do this), but please note that this may reduce the functionality of our website and other websites.

Daft.ie (the website) uses cookies to keep our platform working as you expect it to, to analyse traffic, to prevent non-genuine users and/or malicious software from engaging in abusive activities on our platform, to enable performance and product improvements, to tailor your experience through personalised content and advertising, and to offer features for social media.

\*PCs, tablets, mobile phones and any other internet accessible hardware.

Types of Cookies:
-----------------

First-Party Cookies
-------------------

First-party cookies are directly stored by the website (or domain) you visit. These cookies allow website owners to collect analytics data, remember language settings, and perform other useful functions that provide a good user experience.

Third-Party Cookies
-------------------

Third-party cookies are created by domains that are not the website (or domain) that you are visiting, hence the name third-party. They are typically used for cross-site tracking, retargeting and the personalised advertising.

Cookie Categories:
------------------

Strictly Necessary Cookies
--------------------------

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to navigate the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the platform. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, like shopping baskets or checkout features, cannot be provided.

To prevent non-genuine users and/or malicious software from engaging in abusive activities on our platform, reCAPTCHA and the cookies it requires to function are classified as strictly necessary to ensure the overall safety of our marketplace.

For the privacy of our users, we only use Google Analytics to process obscured and/or non-personally identifiable data to track and understand aggregated usage metrics on our platform, such as number of visitors and unique visits. With these privacy safeguards, Google Analytics and the cookies it requires to function are classified as strictly necessary.

Analytics Cookies
-----------------

These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website, for instance; which pages users visit most often, which links they click on, if they get error messages from certain pages. etc.

These cookies do not collect information that can personally identify a user. Any information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. Their sole purpose is to help improve website functions.

Functional Cookies
------------------

These cookies allow the us to remember some of the choices you make and provide an enhanced, more personalised experience (e.g. remembering your user name and password for login, your search view preferences between sessions etc).

These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise.

They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or posting a comment. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

Advertising Cookies
-------------------

These cookies are used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests as you browse the internet. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign.

They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers.

Quite often marketing or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation.

Please see [here](https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/9012903?hl=en&ref_topic=28145) for an extensive list of Ad technology providers.

You can find more information about the cookies we use and the vendors we work with in the table below:

| Vendor | Cookie | Type | Category | Purpose |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Daft | adserver\_ccid | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie stores information about the last search performed by the user on the site. |
| Daft | AgentID | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is only set for agents and is an identifier in the form of a randomly-generated alphanumeric string which is used to identify a professional real estate agent session. |
| Daft | daft\_last\_search | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie stores the last search of the user. |
| Daft | daft\_uuid | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie has the form of a randomly-generated alphanumeric string which is used to identify suspicious logins for security purposes. |
| Daft | daftID | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie has the form of a randomly-generated alphanumeric string which is used to maintain a user session to keep the session alive between page requests. |
| Daft | OPENSHIFT\_production\_accounts\_SERVERID  <br>OPENSHIFT\_production\_adview\_SERVERID  <br>OPENSHIFT\_production\_adwrite\_SERVERID  <br>OPENSHIFT\_production\_search\_SERVERID | First Party | Strictly Necessary | Used to ensure the session remains on the same server. |
| Daft | session\_opened | First Party | Strictly Necessary | It is used to check when the session of a user started. It is a security check to prevent a session takeover attack. This cookie may only be set after a user logs in. |
| Daft | phishing\_notice | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is used to determine if the phishing notice should be shown to the user or not. |
| Daft | PHPSESSID | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is used for session management. |
| Daft | remember\_me\_user | First Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is used to save the login details of a user so that next time the user comes back using the same computer the user doesn't need to login again. This is set only if "Remember me" is checked by the user. |
| Daft | ReportDownloadCompleteChecker | First Party | Strictly Necessary | Only for private agents. Used to indicate if they have generated a report in the last 30 seconds. |
| Daft | strap\_\*\_\* | First Party | Strictly Necessary | Straplines are horizontal bars at the top of our website which sometimes appear to display a message to the user. This cookie is used to control whether we show the strapline to the user or not. |
| Daft | intercom-session-rnuxs6t2 | First Party | Strictly Necessary | Cookie set when estate agent opens an intercom modal to communicate with Customer Support. |
| Daft | ecommerce | First Party | Functional | This cookie is set to track the checkout process an anonymous user goes through when checking out items in the cart. |
| Daft | unique | First Party | Functional | This cookie consists of a date and randomly-generated alphanumeric string. It is used to generate analytics reports. |
| Daft | DaftCC | First Party | Strictly Necessary | Daft Cookie Consent - to store cookie preferences. |
| Daft | dsch\_partner\_content\_hub\_session | First Party | Marketing | Used to display an iframe with articles from content.daft.ie on the homepage. |
| Daft | showAlert | First Party | Strictly Necessary | Used to show a pop up on search to suggest creating an email alert. |
| AB Tasty | AB Tasty | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie is set by ABTasty. ABTasty is a platform for conversion rate optimization, personalization, customer activation, and testing. This cookie sends all test data (visitorID, test and variant IDs, timestamps). |
| AB Tasty | ABTastySession | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie identifies a unique session. It allows ABTasty to determine that a new session has begun for a user. It only lasts for the length of the session. |
| AT Internet | atidvisitor | Third Party | Analytics | Cookie used by AT Internet for the audience measurement purpose of collect the number of unique site IDs seen by the visitor and to stock the visitor id. |
| AT Internet | atuserid | Third Party | Analytics | Visitor ID for first-party cookie sites. Set by AT Internet. |
| AT Internet | hit.xiti | Third Party | Analytics | Audience measurement |
| AT Internet | idrxvr | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie is set by ATInternet and collects anonymous information when you visit our site to enable the analysis of browsing behavior on the site for optimization |
| CloudFlare | \_\_cfduid | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is set by CloudFlare, a company that provides internet security services. It is used to apply security settings to protect users. |
| donedeal | \_\_gads | Third Party | Advertising | This cookie is associated with the DoubleClick for Publishers service from Google. It is used to register what ads have been shown to the user. |
| donedeal | ddCCT4 | Third Party | Advertising | don't see in in Donedeal cookie list |
| donedeal | \_hjid | Third Party | Advertising | Hotjar cookie. This cookie is set when the customer first lands on a page with the Hotjar script. It is used to persist the random user ID, unique to that site on the browser. This ensures that behavior in subsequent visits to the same site will be attributed to the same user ID. |
| donedeal | \_hjTLDTest | Third Party | Advertising | Hotjar cookie used to capture user behaviour |
| donedeal | NPS\_4fb20f86\_last\_seen | Third Party | Advertising | This Wootric cookie is used so that Wootric knows when they first saw the user on this device after their SDK was enabled. |
| donedeal | xtvrn | Third Party | Advertising | Used by ATInternet to collect annonymous information for user analysis |
| donedeal | xtidc | Third Party | Advertising | Used by ATInternet to collect annonymous information for user analysis |
| donedeal | JSESSIONID | Third Party | Advertising | Session cookie, allows a users logged in status to be recognised when navigating the site |
| donedeal | DDSearchStartTime | Third Party | Advertising | This session cookie is set when a user starts a search so that their search results remain the same until they start a new search. This provides a more seamless experience when searching on DoneDeal. This cookie is strictly necessary as without it a user could experience inconsistencies when viewing our search pages. |
| donedeal | utag\_main | Third Party | Advertising | This cookie name is associated with the Tealium data platform and is used for web analytics |
| donedeal | DDUS | Third Party | Advertising | Stores basic user information to display user's name on page |
| donedeal | \_ga | Third Party | Advertising | Google analytics cookies - annonimisd data |
| donedeal | ab.storage.sessionId | Third Party | Advertising | Used to provide relevant ads to the user |
| donedeal | DDLastViewedAd | Third Party | Advertising | We set set a cookie containing the ad id of the last viewed ad by the user. We then use this to only increment the ad view count once on the ad views. This cookie does not contain any user information. |
| donedeal | DDSEISIUN | Third Party | Advertising | Session cookie, allows a users logged in status to be recognised when navigating the site |
| donedeal | \_\_zlcmid | Third Party | Advertising | Zendesk chat cookie to store users information during chat |
| donedeal | DDSIX | Third Party | Advertising | Verifies the logged in user owns the session for security |
| donedeal | \_gaexp | Third Party | Advertising | Used to determine a user's inclusion in an experiment and the expiry of experiments a user has been included in. |
| Doubleclick | DSID | Third Party | Advertising | Used by doubleclick for remarketing, optimisation, reporting and attribution of online adverts |
| Doubleclick | permutive-id | Third Party | Advertising | This Doubleclick cookie is used for retargeting, optimisation, reporting and attribution of online adverts |
| Doubleclick | cto\_lwid | Third Party | Advertising | Collects data on visitor behaviour from multiple websites, in order to present more relevant advertisement - This also allows the website to limit the number of times that the visitor is shown the same advertisement. |
| Doubleclick | IDE | Third Party | Advertising | Used for serving targeted advertisements that are relevant to users across the web by measuring the conversion rate of ads presented to the user. |
| Doubleclick | permutive-session | Third Party | Advertising | This Doubleclick cookie is used for retargeting, optimisation, reporting and attribution of online adverts |
| Doubleclick | GED\_PLAYLIST\_ACTIVITY | Third Party | Advertising | This cookie is set to count the number of times a specific visitor is shown a specific ad â the cookie enables the advertisers to differentiate the specific ads shown and thereby making the advertising more efficient. |
| Doubleclick.net | pixel | Third Party | Advertising | A/B Tasty is an A/B testing solution that allows you to modify website pages using a visual editor, without writing any code, and without technical knowledge. You can then measure which versions of your pages produce the best results for your objectives. |
| Doubleclick.net | view | Third Party | Advertising | Ads view measurement |
| Doubleclick.net | N3402.daft | Third Party | Advertising | Ads view measurement |
| Eyespy 360 | language | Third Party | Analytics | likely is used to store language preferences, potentially to serve up content in the stored language. |
| Eyespy 360 | auth | Third Party | Analytics | likely used to allow users interact with Eyespy Virtual Tours creation modal as a daft user |
| Google | \_\_gads | Third Party | Advertising | This cookie is associated with the DoubleClick for Publishers service from Google. It is used to register what ads have been shown to the user. |
| Google | S   | Third Party | Analytics | Cookie from Google that collects certain information used to help improve services, including the pages users visit most often and whether users get error messages from certain pages |
| Google | SIDCC | Third Party | Advertising | A security cookie to protect a userâs data from unauthorized access |
| Google | DV  | Third Party | Advertising | Security cookie to authenticate users, prevent fraudulent use of login credentials, and protect user data from unauthorized parties. |
| Google | OTZ | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie used by Google Analytics that provides an aggregate analysis of Website visitors |
| Google | 1p-conversion | Third Party | Advertising | Ads conversion measurement |
| Google | CONSENT | Third Party | Advertising | Used by Google to remember the userâs consent. It contains a timestamp |
| Google | 1P\_JAR | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie used to gather website statistics and track conversion rates |
| Google | ga-audiences | Third Party | Advertising | Audience measurement |
| Google | gen\_204 | Third Party | Analytics | Ads view measurement |
| Google | activeview | Third Party | Advertising | Ads view measurement |
| Google | activity | Third Party | Advertising | Ads view measurement |
| Google AdSense | \_gcl\_au | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | Used by Google AdSense for experimenting with advertisement efficiency across websites using their services |
| Google Adwords | AID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | SID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | SAPISID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | APISID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | HSID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | NID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | SSID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | ANID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google Adwords | APISID | Third Party | Advertising | Cookie from Google adwords. These are used to optimize ad offerings on the google display network and search engine. |
| Google AdWords Conversion | https://googleads.g.doubleclick.net/pagead/conversion/ | Third Party | Advertising | Ads conversion measurement |
| Google Analytics | \_gat\_UA-1011713-1 | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | Google analytics cookies captures annonimisd data to understand how users engage with the site |
| Google Analytics | \_gat\_gtag\_UA\_1011713\_31 | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | Google analytics cookies captures annonimisd data to understand how users engage with the site |
| Google Analytics | \_gat\_UA-1011713-33 | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | Google analytics cookies captures annonimisd data to understand how users engage with the site |
| Google Analytics | \_hjTLDTest | Third Party | Analytics | Hotjar cookie used to capture user behaviour |
| Google Analytics | collect | Third Party | Analytics | Measure traffic and behaviour on site |
| Google Tag Manager | gtm\_auth | Third Party | Analytics | Cookie from Google Tag Manager. These are used for debugging purposes for tag management and expires when the browsing sessions end. Cookie won't be set for visitors, only people who has access to GTM and using Debug pane. |
| Google Tag Manager | gtm\_debug | Third Party | Analytics | Cookie from Google Tag Manager. These are used for debugging purposes for tag management and expires when the browsing sessions end. Cookie won't be set for visitors, only people who has access to GTM and using Debug pane. |
| Google Tag Manager | gtm\_preview | Third Party | Analytics | Cookie from Google Tag Manager. These are used for debugging purposes for tag management and expires when the browsing sessions end. Cookie won't be set for visitors, only people who has access to GTM and using Debug pane. |
| Google Universal Analytics | \_ga | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | Google analytics cookies captures annonimisd data to understand how users engage with the site |
| Google Universal Analytics | \_gid | Third Party | Strictly Necessary | Google analytics cookies captures annonimisd data to understand how users engage with the site |
| HotJar | \_hjDoneTestersWidgets | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie is set once a visitor submits their information in the Recruit User Testers widget. It is used to ensure that the same form does not re-appear if it has already been filled in. Lasts 365 days |
| Hotjar | \_hjid | Third Party | Analytics | Hotjar cookie used to capture user behaviour |
| HotJar | \_hjDonePolls | Third Party | Analytics | Hotjar cookie set as soon as a user completes a poll to ensure they don't get asked to fill it in again |
| HotJar | \_hjIncludedInSessionSample | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie is associated with web analytics functionality and services from Hot Jar. It uniquely identifies a visitor during a single browser session and indicates they are included in an audience sample. |
| HotJar | \_hjMinimizedPolls | Third Party | Analytics | Hotjar cookie set as soon as a user completes a poll to ensure they don't get asked to fill it in again |
| HotJar | \_hjShownFeedbackMessage | Third Party | Analytics | Hotjar cookie that is set when a visitor minimizes or completes Incoming Feedback. |
| HotJar | \_hjClosedSurveyInvites | Third Party | Analytics | Hotjar cookie used to store user interaction with an invitation to survey modal |
| HotJar | \_hjMinimizedTestersWidgets | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie is set once a visitor minimizes a Recruit User Testers widget. It is used to ensure that the widget stays minimizes when the visitor navigates through the site. Lasts 365 days |
| Hotjar | \_\_hssrc | Third Party | Analytics | Hubspot cookie implemented by HotJar used to gather information about user interaction |
| Hotjar | \_\_hstc | Third Party | Analytics | Hubspot cookie implemented by HotJar used for tracking visitors. |
| Hotjar | ajs\_anonymous\_id | Third Party | Analytics | A randomly generated string used to count how many people visit us by tracking if they have visited before |
| Hotjar | ajs\_group\_id | Third Party | Analytics | Set by HotJar. This cookie tracks visitor usage and events within the website. Lifespan is determined by HotJar. |
| Hotjar | ajs\_user\_id | Third Party | Analytics | Set by HotJar. This cookie helps track visitor usage, events, target marketing, and can also measure application performance and stability |
| Hotjar | hubspotutk | Third Party | Analytics | Hubspot cookie implemented by HotJar and used for to keep track of a visitor's identity. This cookie is passed to HubSpot on form submission and used when deduplicating contacts |
| Hotjar | \_fbp | Third Party | Analytics | Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products |
| ScorecardResearch | UID | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie provides a uniquely assigned, machine-generated user ID and gathers data about activity on the website. |
| ScorecardResearch | UIDR | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie is set to measure the number and behavior of website visitors coming and going. |
| Tealium | \_gat\_tealium\_0 | Third Party | Analytics | Tealium Google Analytics Integration used to decide whether to send google analytics events to a specific account or not. |
| Tealium | utag\_main | Third Party | Analytics | This cookie name is associated with the Tealium data platform and is used for web analytics |
| Wootric | NPS\_215a2284\_surveyed | Third Party | Analytics | This Wootric cookie is a flag that indicates if a user has taken a survey on DoneDeal already and prevents him/her from being oversampled. |
| Wootric | NPS\_215a2284\_last\_seen | Third Party | Analytics | This Wootric cookie is used so that Wootric knows when they first saw the user on this device after their SDK was enabled. |
| Wootric | NPS\_215a2284\_throttle | Third Party | Analytics | This is a Wootric cookie that mirrors the resurvey throttle based on last response or decline date. |

From time to time, there may be changes to these third-party cookies such as name changes, etc. We will endeavour to keep the table updated and encourage you to review the Privacy Policies of each of the third parties listed above.

This Cookie Policy forms part of our overall [Privacy Policy](https://daft.ie/privacy/#privacy).

© Daft Media Limited 1997 - 2024

* [Privacy](https://publish.daft.ie/privacy/)/[Legal](https://publish.daft.ie/legal/)
* [Consent choices](javascript:Didomi.preferences.show())

Sites:
